In today's video, we'll be looking at
Google's Notebook Alm that turns any
document, YouTube video, or resource you
give it into your personal research
assistant. And from what I have seen, I
would consider this the most criminally
underrated tool in the entire AI space.
And yes, it can even make podcasts. So,
here's the deal. With Notebook LM, you
get free massive advantages. First, you
can start using it completely for free
just with a Google account. Second, it
only answers from your documents or
links. No more AI hallucinations. And
third, you can chat with up to 50
documents at once. And that's the free
plan. If I'm on the pro plan, it's 300.
Just for reference, 50 documents are 25
million words that you can put into this
thing. Now, it won't look at the data on
all of the internet for you like a
Google search or maybe a chat GPD search
would do. But for research, this thing
is unbeatable. And using it is super
simple. All you need is a Google account
to log in, some PDFs, YouTube videos or
websites to analyze, and a basic
understanding of a chat interface like
you would find in chat GPT. Once you're
logged in on the notebookm.google.com,
you just click create new notebook. And
here comes the magic part. It asks you
to add different sources. So, what I'll
do for this tutorial, I'll just upload
this research paper that I happen to
really enjoy. It's about the potential
of AI replacing a therapist. Not to
spoil it, but it's definitely not there
yet, but that's a research topic we'll
be building our notebook around here
today. I'll rename the notebook to AI
therapy project. And notebook
immediately creates a summary of
everything that you add to the sources
here on the left side. And then if I ask
questions down here, you will notice
that it answers them based on just the
documents that I added to it with little
references next to them showing you
exactly where it found this information.
You can use this just like chat GPT
asking follow-up questions to get to
what you're looking for. Now, if there's
YouTube videos like this one that I
particularly enjoyed, I'll just go here,
say add, link to a YouTube video,
insert, and now my notebook will update
with these sources. And here's the first
pro tip. If you only want to chat with
one source, let's say I only want to
talk to this YouTube video. Make sure
that just this check mark is set. I'll
restart my chat up here and ask a brand
new question. And now the answer will
only be based upon this source. Now, if
I really like this answer and I want to
save this for future reference, you
click save to note. And that's sort of
like noting something down in your very
own notebook. But here's the killer
feature that you might have seen
already. People use this all over social
media. When you have your sources loaded
in here, you can just click this button,
audio overview, and it will create a
podcast that summarizes all of these
sources for you. So you don't have to
read about all the documents that you
add to the sources. You can listen to
them, which I don't know about you, but
me as an avid YouTube and audiobook
enjoyer, I do personally prefer this to
reading articles and such. And here's a
secret many people overlook. If you go
to the free dots, you can customize it
and you can specify the tone, the
length, and most importantly, the focus
of this podcast.
>> Can AI, you know, artificial
intelligence actually replace humans?
especially when it comes to something as
deeply personal, as nuanced as therapy
and emotional support.
>> That's such a critical question right
now. And we've got some well fascinating
material to explore.
>> It sounds incredibly good and it's
accurate to the source materials. And if
you want, you can even go into this
interactive mode where you yourself can
start interacting with the hosts. Hey,
what's up?
>> Hey there, listeners. So glad you're
joining us. We're just kicking off this
week's deep dive.
>> Yeah, glad you're here. We're diving
into something super relevant today.
>> Two more killer features to be aware of
here. On the one hand, you can do the
same things for video overviews where it
sort of creates a PowerPoint
presentation with a voice over guiding
you through the whole thing in video
form. And two, you can turn the content
into an interactive mind map or one of
these formats over here. So, at the very
core, what matters here for somebody new
to this application? Well, the free
account lets you add 50 sources here on
the left and you can generate three to
five audio reviews a day. And remember,
it will not browse the web, access
content behind payw walls, or look into
its own knowledge base. It's just an AI
that sticks to the sources you give it,
citing everything precisely. You can use
it for any research purpose, book
summaries, meeting notes, trip planning,
studying, or when you're learning about
new topics. But it doesn't stop there.
Let me tell you, I've even consulted
some lawyers that use this to get an
unfair advantage in the courtroom. They
throw off the sources relating to the
case into here, generate a bunch of
podcasts, and get a level of information
that no human without a tool like this
could ever consume. And there you go. We
just turned multiple dense documents
into an interactive AI assistant and a
podcast summary in just a few minutes.
If you want something to try right now,
upload your latest free documents into
here and ask Notebook LM about the
patterns that you might have missed. And
if you enjoyed this video and want to
see more quick tutorials like this,
check out this playlist over here. And
with that being said, my name is Igor
and I hope you have a wonderful day.